# Daniel Duclos-Cavalcanti

## Computer Engineer

516-912-7975 | New York, NY | U.S. Citizen | me@duclos.dev | www.duclos.dev | linkedin | github

### Summary

Creative thinker and problem-solver with a masters and bachelors in traditional german electrical engineering. Today, I am in New York, collaborating on exciting research with Dr.Sivaraman (NYU) that envisions a financial exchange on the cloud.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, C++, Python, Golang, Rust, Bash, Lua, VHDL, Tcl, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Tools: Terraform, Docker, Packer, AWS, Google Cloud (GCP), Git, Unix Shell, Makefile, CMake, Linux, Jenkins, Vim Technologies: Cloud Computing, Computer Networking, Machine Learning, Concurrency, FPGA, RTOS, IoT, HPC

Frameworks: ZeroMQ, DPDK, TCP/UDP/IP, Tensorflow, TFLite, Numpy, Pandas, OpenMPI, OpenMP

Certificates: UCSD: Data Structures Fundamentals, UT Austin: Embedded Systems - uC I/O

#### EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

Jul 2022 – Oct 2022

TU Munich Munich, Germany
• Generated reports to establish a Design-Space Exploration framework to guide ML model deployments.

- Evaluated and compared the performance of various Machine Learning models across GPUs, CPUs and TPUs.
- Analyzed USB traffic through PyShark between the host and externally added TPUs.

#### Embedded Engineer Intern

Aug 2021 – Jan 2022

Ottobrunn, Germany

- Developed tooling for state simulations of their electric motor via Linux's virtual CAN interface and mock APIs.
- Added unit-tests and code coverage to safety critical features of their motor drive embedded controller.
- Extended an automatic firmware update functionality used by over 20 clients.
- Streamlined build and testing workflows via Jenkins and CMake for a team of over 10 engineers.

## Tutor - Embedded Systems Programming Lab

Apr 2021 – Aug 2021

TU Munich

Molabo GmbH

Munich, Germany

• Supervised and aided 20+ students on their final embedded FreeRTOS laboratory projects in C.

## Publications

#### Jasper: Fair Multicast for Financial Exchanges in the Cloud | (Paper)

Jan 24 – Present

- Novel cloud hosted financial exchange achieving low latency multicast service for up to 1000 market participants.
- Achieves better scalability and around 50% lower latency than the multicast service provided by AWS.
- Used kernel-bypass techniques (DPDK) to achieve ultra-low latency at up to 35K multicast packet rate.

#### Projects

## **Open-MPI Value Iteration** | *C++*, *Multi-Threaded*, *HPC*

Sept 2021 – Feb 2022

• Asynchronous value iteration model to distribute workload on an HPC cluster.

#### Hamming Code Error Detection | C, VHDL, FPGA, SoC

Oct 2022 – March 2023

• Error detection/correction algorithm for packet transmission on Microsemi's SF2 FPGA/SoC.

#### FreeRTOS-SpaceInvaders | C, RTOS, Multi-Threaded

Aug 2020 – March 2021

• Implemented the famous arcade game as a multi-threaded FreeRTOS application in C.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### New York University: Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences

Sept 2023 – May 2024

Computer Science - Visiting Non-Degree Graduate Student

GPA 4.0

- Co-Authored Publication: Jasper: Fair Multicast for Financial Exchanges in the Cloud
- Related Coursework: Operating Systems, Technologies in Finance

#### Technical University of Munich

Oct 2020 - Sept 2024

Expected GPA: 3.2

M.Sc. Electrical and Computer Engineering

• M.Sc. Thesis: VM Selection Heuristic for Multicast Overlay Trees in the Cloud

• Related Coursework: Machine Learning Methods and Tools, Embedded Design for Machine Learning, Chips Multicore Processors, Secure SoCs for IoT, High Performance Computing for Machine Intelligence

#### Technical University of Munich

Oct 2016 - Sept 2020

B.Sc. Electrical and Computer Engineering